townshoes.ca 2017-12-28

# Privacy Policy | Town Shoes

Town Shoes Limited is 100% committed to upholding your privacy. This privacy policy describes how we use personal information collected in our retail store locations or on this website. Please read this privacy policy before using the website or providing any personal information in our retail stores. By using the website or providing your personal information in our stores, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy. These practices may be changed, but any changes will be posted and changes will only apply to activities and information on a going forward, not retroactive basis. Note, the privacy practices set forth in this privacy policy are for this website and Town Shoes Limited stores in Canada only. If you link to other websites, please review the privacy policies posted at those sites.

#### **COLLECTION OF INFORMATION**

There are two (2) types of information collected by Town Shoes limited: "Personal" such as names, postal addresses, and email addresses & "Non-Personal" such as store shopped at or products viewed.Any personal information you provide is used to fulfill your specific request. This information is only used to fulfill your specific request, unless you give us permission to use it in another manner, for example to add you to one of our mailing lists. Where we ask you to provide personal information, you always have the choice of not providing the information. However, if you do so, we may not be able to provide you with the service or benefit which you are requesting.

In some cases, we may combine personal information with non-personal information. Where we do this, the combined information will be treated by us as if it were personal information for as long as it remains combined.

#### **WHAT DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR?**

Personal and non-personal information that we collect from you is used for a number of purposes:

  1. It helps us to improve the content of our website or retail store environment.
  2. It permits us to better understand our customer's needs.
  3. It enables us to communicate with our customer's.
  4. It is used to make business and financial decisions within our company
  5. It allows us to comply with legal and regulatory requirements.

Unless consent is given, we do not use or disclose your personal information for the purposes other than those for which it was collected.

####  **COOKIE/TRACKING TECHNOLOGY AND SOCIAL MEDIA**

This website may use cookie and tracking technology. Cookie and tracking technology are useful for understanding how visitors use our website and can help customize the website for visitors. Personal information cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology, however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests.

Town Shoes Limited utilizes social media networks such as Facebook, Twitter and Instagram to market its products and services. Certain social networks allow ad targeting of customers and the ability for customers to share likes and interests with your friends / contacts. When you click on a social media plug-in, a link to our site may appear in the "Likes and Interests" section of your Facebook or other social media website profile. By using a social media plug-ins, you consent to receiving communications from us for all of these purposes. For more information about social media plug-in protocols and their impact on your privacy rights, please visit the appropriate social media website help centre (such as the Facebook Help Center) to find out more.

We may use the services of third parties to collect and use anonymous information about your visits to and interactions with our website through the use of technologies such as cookies to personalize advertisements for goods and services. To learn more, or to opt-out of receiving online display advertisements tailored to your interests by our third party partners, visit the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada at http://youradchoices.ca/choices.

#### **EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS**

We will be communicating to you mainly through our email communication channels. When you provide us your email address, you provide express and/or implied consent "to opt in" to receive communications from Town Shoes Limited brands within the guidelines and limitations listed below.  With consent, Town Shoes Limited may notify you of specific products and services such as promotions, contests and surveys that you may be interested in, or information about your order or loyalty program membership.  The option to "opt out" or "unsubscribe" after you have "opted in" will always be available.

#### **YOUR IMPLIED COMMUNICATIONS CONSENT**

Your consent is **implied** in some cases where we have collected your personal information. Under **Implied** consent, we will only send you email communications when it directly applies to the business purpose of your original request.  Some examples of **implied** consent are when you make a purchase on a Town Shoes Limited website and are sent a purchase or shipping confirmation, or communication with our Customer Service or Store Associates.  In these cases, your **implied** consent will automatically expire once the business purpose of your transaction has completed and you will not be added to any email marketing lists beyond these actions.  

When you join the Shoe Lovers Rewards program by providing your email address in a Town Shoes Limited retail store, your consent is also considered **implied** to receive email communications about your Shoe Lovers Rewards membership.  All Shoe Lovers Rewards subscriptions that fall under **implied** consent guidelines **** will expire from our email database within 24 months of your last interaction with Town Shoes Limited. For example: if you join the Shoe Lovers Rewards program and make a transaction at a Town Shoes Limited brand store on June 30th, 2017 your consent to receive communications from this specific banner is implied and will expire June 29th, 2019, unless you choose to withdraw or change your consent prior to that date.  You will always maintain the option to "opt out" from having your information used for this purpose.

#### **YOUR EXPRESS COMMUNICATIONS CONSENT**

Your consent to receive electronic communications can be considered express, in some cases.  Under express consent guidelines, Town Shoes Limited may send you email marketing messages such as specific products and services, promotions, contests and surveys that you may be interested in.  There is no expiry to express consent, unless you request to "opt out" or "unsubscribe".  We will only consider your consent express in the event you have specifically requested or approved to receive email marketing communications.  Examples of where this consent may be provided are via website sign up, in-store digital keypad, or responding to a direct communication request for consent.  

 **

#### **FORWARDING OR SHARING EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS**

**

If you choose to forward or share email communications that you've received from us, you will be assuming the responsibility for the email communication and therefore Town Shoes Limited will not be held responsible for any liabilities incurred.

#### **WITHDRAWING YOUR CONSENT**

We will always provide you with the opportunity to "opt out" or "unsubscribe" within each communication we send to you.  Shoe Lovers Rewards members who complete their profiles on our website also have the ability to change or withdraw their consent at any time via our website.  This can be done by logging into your account, clicking on "Update Personal Details" and adjusting your email preferences.

#### **DISTRIBUTION OF INFORMATION**

We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these companies for their own marketing purposes.

#### **PROTECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We use current security, administrative and technical measures to protect against loss, misuse and interception of your personal information. Only authorized employees, agents and contractors (who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential) have access to this information. All Town Shoes Limited employees and partners must abide by this Policy.

It is important that you understand that we cannot protect personal information which is disclosed by directly you to third parties. Likewise, it is important that you take steps to prevent unauthorized access to your computer system, your Shoe Lovers Rewards account and related passwords.Town Shoes Limited will not be liable for any disclosure of your personal information in these circumstances. Although we do not take responsibility for any theft, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, loss, alteration or destruction of data, we do take reasonable precautions to prevent such occurrences.

#### **CHILDREN**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we are notified that we have collected personal information of a child under 13, subject to verification, we will delete this information.

#### **RETENTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We will retain your personal information only for as long as we continue to need it to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.You can also request that we remove your information from our records. Subject to our requirements for continued retention of your information, for example, for billing, audit, or warranty purposes, we will make every reasonable effort to honour your request.

#### **PRIVACY CONTACT INFORMATION**

If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our privacy policy you may contact us using the information below:   
Call toll free to **1-888-874-6326** from 9am-5pm ET Monday to Friday or email us at [**service@townshoes.ca**](mailto:service@townshoes.ca)

#### **CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Since our business is constantly evolving, we may change our Privacy Policy from time to time. When we make a change to our Privacy Policy we will promptly post an updated Privacy Policy on our website.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on: **October 6, 2017**
